<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>openshift on Terminal</title>
    <link>https://cesarvr.io/tags/openshift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in openshift on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cesarvr.io/tags/openshift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps</title>
      <link>https://cesarvr.io/post/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cesarvr.io/post/devops/</guid>
      <description>To take full advantage of Openshift we should change the way we build, deploy and run software. To spark that change here some good engineering principles (that later will become buzzwords on their own) extracted from an interview with Werner Vogel Amazon&#39;s CTO on 2006.
Encapsulation  We went through a period of serious introspection and concluded that a service-oriented architecture would give us the level of isolation that would allow us to build many software components rapidly and independently&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Deploying Node.JS Applications</title>
      <link>https://cesarvr.io/post/self-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cesarvr.io/post/self-deploy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few days ago I was watching in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XPC-hFL-4lU&#34;&gt;Youtube a talk&lt;/a&gt; given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kelseyhightower&#34;&gt;Kelsey Hightower&lt;/a&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;Self Deploying Kubernetes Applications&amp;rdquo;. In this talk which is a bit old now (over a year) he was demoing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34;&gt;Golang&lt;/a&gt; application capable of running locally but also capable of &lt;em&gt;magically&lt;/em&gt; deploy itself into a Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaining Builds In Openshift</title>
      <link>https://cesarvr.io/post/ocp-chainbuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 11:18:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cesarvr.io/post/ocp-chainbuild/</guid>
      <description>New application Creating a Node.js application in Openshift is simple:
oc login -u user oc new-project hello # Assuming you are logged and you have a project you can start here. oc new-app --name node-app nodejs~https://github.com/cesarvr/hello-world-nodejs #new app using nodejs:latest (Node.js 8) This command will create the backbone (BuildConfig, DeploymentConfig and Service) to orchestrate the different stages from source code to a running application.
The size problem But this nice abstraction come with a cost, to explain what I mean, let&#39;s review size of our final image using du:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple CI/CD</title>
      <link>https://cesarvr.io/post/okd-cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 11:18:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cesarvr.io/post/okd-cicd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get your Java source code, tested, packaged, containerized and deployed in four steps. We are going to defined 4 decoupled steps that
you can improve with more complex use cases in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>